This video is all about density. Is
这段视频主要讲的是密度。 城市是否
there a best or optimal density for
存在最佳或最优密度
cities? Now, to start, I think we can
？ 首先，我认为我们可以
eliminate the extremes right off the
立即排除极端情况
bat. At one end is zero. Zero means
。 一端为零。 零表示
nobody's living there. That could be for
那里无人居住。
you if you want to get away from it all,
如果你想远离尘嚣，那或许很适合你，
but it's not possible to give 8 billion
但不可能给 80 亿
people their own remote Canadian island.
人口每人一个偏远的加拿大岛屿。
But is more density always better?
但是密度越高就一定越好吗？
Should we all be living on the most
我们都应该生活在
dense place on the planet? If I were to
地球上人口密度最高的地方吗？ 如果我
ask you where the most dense city on
问你地球上人口密度最高的城市
Earth is, I bet your response would be
是哪里，我敢打赌你的回答会是
somewhere like Manhattan or Singapore or
曼哈顿、新加坡或香港之类的地方
Hong Kong. And those would all be really
。 这些都是
good guesses, but they would all be
很好的猜测，但
really wrong. New York City is the 100th
实际上都是错误的。 纽约市是世界上人口密度排名第100位的
most dense city in the world. Singapore
城市。 新加坡
isn't in the top 100 at all, and neither
和香港都没有进入前100名
is Hong Kong. I point this out because
。 我指出这一点是因为
we as humans don't really have a good
我们人类对城市密度并没有真正很好的
natural understanding of urban density.
自然理解。
Let's take a look at the equation to
让我们来看一下这个等式，以
understand why. Density is computed by
了解其中的原因。 人口密度的计算方法是用
a place by that place's total land area.
一个地方的人口数量除以该地方的总土地面积。
Let's look down here first. Total land
我们先往下看。 总土地
area is often a city's boundaries. If a
面积通常指城市的边界。 如果一个
city has a lot of parks, it reduces the
城市有很多公园，就会降低
population density of a city. Hong
该城市的人口密度。
Kong's area is actually pretty large and
香港面积其实相当大，而且
includes lots of natural areas. If you
包含很多自然区域。 如果
were just to compute the density for the
只计算
builtup area of Hong Kong, it would be
香港建成区的密度，它
the world easily. What is the most dense
很容易就能跻身世界人口密度最高的三个城市之列。
city in the world then? It's Giza,
那么，世界上人口密度最高的城市是哪里呢？ 这里是
Egypt. Its population density is four
埃及吉萨。 它的人口密度是
times that of New York City. While it
纽约市的四倍。 虽然它
certainly looks like a dense city, how
看起来确实是一座人口密集的城市，但
could it really outdo cities like New
它怎么可能比得上
York or Hong Kong with their massive
纽约或香港这样拥有
highrises? In part, it's because
摩天大楼的城市呢？ 部分原因是因为它的
boundaries are tightly drawn around it.
边界被严格划定。
It's basically a massive suburb of
它基本上是开罗的一个大型郊区
Cairo, surrounded on all sides by more
，四周都被更多的
urbanization, and you're not going to
城市化地区包围，而且
find many large parks in Giza to dilute
在吉萨你找不到很多大型公园来缓解
the density of the city. Another thing
城市的密度。
about density is we often equate it with
关于密度，我们常常会把它与
tall buildings. This is how we can juice
高楼大厦联系起来。 这就是我们
up the numbers in the numerator of our
增加等式分子中数字的方法
equation. If you fit a bit more people
。 如果在相同的区域内容纳更多的人
in the same area, density goes up.
，密度就会增加。   将
Stacking people is a smart way of doing
人员堆叠起来是一种巧妙的方法
that. But there is another way. And no,
。 但还有另一种方法。 不，
it's not burying people. It's making
这不是埋葬死人。 它导致
homes smaller and putting more people in
房屋面积缩小，而居住人数却增加
those homes. Despite all of the towers
。 尽管曼哈顿高楼林立
in Manhattan, it was actually more dense
，但实际上
in 1910. That's because people were
1910年人口密度更高。这是因为当时人们
living in tenement apartments that
居住在内部像这样的廉租公寓里
looked like this on the inside. These
。 这些
buildings were rarely taller than six
建筑物很少超过六层楼高
stories, but it beat out the density of
，但其密度却超过了
skyscrapers. That's what's happening in
摩天大楼。 这就是
Giza. Now, second on the list for most
吉萨正在发生的事情。 现在，人口密度最高的城市排名第二的
dense cities is Manila, which also has a
是马尼拉，它的
tight boundary. It has skyscrapers, but
边界也很狭窄。 这里有摩天大楼，但
most of its population density comes
大部分人口密度都集中在像
from neighborhoods that look like this.
这样的街区。
Same with Mallay, the fifth most dense
马来亚的情况也类似，它是世界上人口密度第五高的
city in the world. No skyscrapers in
城市。 周围没有摩天大楼
sight, just a tight boundary and not a
，只有狭窄的边界，
lot of public open space. Okay, now that
公共开放空间不多。 好了，现在
we have an understanding of how density
我们已经了解了密度
is calculated, we can really start
是如何计算的，我们可以真正开始
thinking about the optimal density. So,
思考最佳密度了。 那么，
let's take a journey around the world to
让我们环游世界，探寻
city after the bike bell.
自行车铃声之后，城市的最佳人口密度是多少。
Now, obviously, best or optimal density
显然，最佳或最优密度
is a judgment call. We all prefer cities
是一个判断性问题。 我们都喜欢
of different densities, and even your
不同密度的城市，甚至你
idea of a perfect density may be
认为的完美密度也可能与
different than mine because we prefer
我不同，因为我们喜欢的
different densities with home sizes. Not
密度和房屋大小各不相同。 并非
everyone wants to live in a studio
每个人都想住在高层建筑
apartment 20 stories up in a high-rise.
20层楼高的单身公寓里。
Right now, I have my family of five in a
目前，我和家人五口住在一套
1300T home. That feels pretty good to
1300吨的房子里。 我觉得挺好的
me, but I've had conversations with
，但我跟
people who feel cramped with a family of
一些人聊过，他们一家
four and 2,000 ft². And there are plenty
四口住在 2000 平方英尺的房子里感觉很拥挤。
of people out there, I'm sure, who think
我相信，肯定有很多人认为
I'm absolutely living large in 1300 ft².
我住在 1300 平方英尺的房子里已经过着非常奢华的生活了。
They may be thinking, "Hey, he doesn't
他们可能会想，“嘿，他
need my Patreon support." To which I
不需要我的 Patreon 支持。” 对此我的
say, "Maybe not, but California is
回答是：“也许不是，但加州的生活
expensive." Similarly, there may be a
成本很高。” 同样，可能有
lot of people out there who will never
很多人永远不会
want to live in a neighborhood as dense
想住在像
as, say, Williamsburg in Brooklyn or
布鲁克林威廉斯堡或
central Paris. For many, this is the
巴黎市中心那样人口密集的社区。 对许多人来说，这是
ideal density for them. I get that. But
理想的密度。 我明白了。 但
there are densities that seem to result
有些人口密度似乎能造就充满
in vibrant cities that provide a high
活力的城市，
standard of living for residents. Those
为居民提供高水平的生活。 这些
residents have access to jobs, food,
居民可以方便地在附近获得工作、食物、
medical care, third places, and more
医疗保健、第三空间等资源
nearby. They can get to those places
。 他们可以
using a variety of transportation types.
使用多种交通工具到达这些地方。
Their environment encourages healthy
他们的生活环境鼓励健康的
living. And the city is generally good
生活方式。 而且这座城市总体上
for the environment. So, what density
对环境有益。 那么，什么样的密度
can do all of those things? The optimal
才能做到所有这些呢？
density, thinking as a planner, is a
从规划者的角度来看，最佳密度是
transit supportive density. That means
能够支持公共交通的密度。 这意味着
there are enough people to support
有足够的人口来支持
frequent transit service. When you have
频繁的公共交通服务。 当
more people using transit, you naturally
更多的人使用公共交通工具时，自然会让
get people out of their cars, have more
人们放弃开车，更多的
people walking and being healthy, and
人步行出行，保持健康，并且
have more stuff to do within walking and
在步行和公共交通范围内有更多的事情可做
transit distance. This is another
。 这是
example of the land use transportation
土地利用与交通运输联系的另一个例子
connection. My favorite connection since
。 这是我自彩虹桥段以来最喜欢的连接
the rainbow one. Density is a measure of
。 密度是衡量
land use, but transportation is so
土地利用的指标，但交通
integral to good land use that we're
对于良好的土地利用至关重要，因此我们
using a transit threshold to define it.
使用交通阈值来定义它。
The more you spend time thinking about
你花在思考
city planning, the more you end up
城市规划上的时间越多，最终就越会
thinking about the transportation land
思考交通和土地
use connection. So, what is transit
利用之间的关系。 那么，什么是公共交通
supportive density? It depends on what
支持密度？ 这取决于
kind of transit you want to support. I'm
你想支持哪种类型的交通运输。 我
area in this, but I'll also list acres,
这里将以足球场为单位来表示我的区域，但我也会列出英亩，因为英亩
which is the more common unit here in
是美国这里更常见的单位
the United States. And I should add that
。 我还要补充一点，
we're using gross density, which
我们使用的是总密度，其中
includes space for parks and roads and
包括公园、道路和
non-housing uses. If you want to support
非住宅用途的空间。 如果你想支持
infrequent once per hour bus service,
每小时一班的公交车服务，那么
you need about 21 people per football
每个足球场大约需要 21 人
pitch. That's about eight homes per
。 每个球场大约有八栋房子
pitch. You can think about it as low
。 你可以把它想象成
density suburbia. Once per hour bus
低密度郊区。 每小时一班的公交车
service is really not terribly useful,
服务实在没什么用，
but I guess it's better than absolutely
但我想总比没有强
nothing. If you have a dream of putting
。 如果你梦想
a subway station in your suburb, you can
在郊区建一个地铁站，那么你到此为止吧
stop right here. There just aren't
。
enough people to ride it. If we want to
乘坐的人太少了。 如果我们想把
bump that up to 30 minute bus service,
公交服务时间缩短到 30 分钟，那么
we'll need 30 people per football pitch
每个足球场需要 30 人，
or about 12 homes per pitch. Now we're
或者每个球场大约需要 12 户人家。 现在我们
getting into neighborhoods that have
进入了一些
more dense single family housing. Maybe
独栋住宅密度较高的社区。
there are duplexes or ADUs in the
后院可能有复式住宅或附属住宅单元
backyard. Lots of older single family
。 许多较老的独栋
neighborhoods, like historic
住宅区，例如历史
neighborhoods, fit this density.
街区，都符合这种密度。
Halfhour bus service, it's okay. You
半小时的巴士服务，还可以。 你
could use it reliably to commute, but
可以用它可靠地通勤，但这
it's definitely not ideal. According to
绝对不是理想的选择。 根据
this research paper by Eric Guerrera and
Eric Guerrera 和
Robert Cerero, you'll need about 53
Robert Cerero 的这篇研究论文，要支持轻轨服务，每个足球场大约需要 53
people per football pitch or about 21
人，或者
homes per pitch in a station area to
车站区域每个球场大约需要 21 户人家
support light rail service. That's
。 这
almost triple the density of a typical
几乎是
modern single family neighborhood. We're
现代典型独栋住宅社区密度的三倍。 我们
talking about town homes now, maybe
现在说的是联排别墅，可能偶尔也会有一些
small apartment buildings here and
小型公寓楼
there. You can see these kind of
。
densities required if you look at modern
如果你观察一下
around modern light rail station areas.
现代轻轨站周边地区的现代公交导向型开发项目，就能看到这种所需的密度。
These areas often have mixeduse
这些地区通常采用混合用途
development with restaurants, cafes,
开发，街边设有餐厅、咖啡馆、
Pilates studios, and other amenities
普拉提工作室和其他便利设施，
light rail. That's great, but what about
轻轨上方则是住宅。 那太好了，但是
full-on metro service? Guerrera and
完整的地铁服务呢？  Guerrera 和
Cerero computed that you'll need about
Cerero 计算得出，
80 people per football pitch to make
每个足球场大约需要 80 人才能使
metro service viable. That's about 32
地铁服务可行。 那大约是32户
homes. I'd argue probably actually need
人家。 我认为，
a little bit more these days to justify
如今建设
a metro station, particularly as transit
地铁站可能需要更多资金，尤其是在美国的交通
construction costs continue to rise here
建设成本持续上涨的情况下
in the US. Now, we're looking at a lot
。 现在，我们看到很多
of five over one buildings, which means
五层楼高的建筑，这意味着
five floors of homes over one floor of
五层是住宅，一层是
retail, restaurant, and service uses.
零售、餐饮和服务用途。
Six stories seems to be a good density
六层楼似乎是地铁服务的一个不错的密度标准
floor for metro service. I'd argue
。 但我认为，要想
though that to have a really good robust
拥有真正良好、稳健的
metro service, you probably need
地铁服务，至少在车站区域，可能需要
something closer to 10 stories
接近 10 层楼的建筑
areas. Here in the United States, try to
。 在美国，试着
picture Washington DC. In 1910, Congress
想象一下华盛顿特区的情景。  1910 年，国会
passed the heightened buildings acts
通过了《高层建筑法》，将
that restricted buildings to 130 ft or
建筑物高度限制在 130 英尺（
about 40 meters. That way, people could
约 40 米）以内。 这样一来，人们
still see all the monuments and
仍然可以看到所有纪念碑和
important buildings rising over the
重要建筑耸立在
artificially low skyline. Despite this
人为降低的天际线之上。 尽管存在这种
restriction, DC still feels like a great
限制，华盛顿特区仍然感觉像是一个很棒的
city with good transit, walkability, and
城市，拥有良好的交通、适宜步行的环境和
a good mix of uses. It's also helped by
良好的用途组合。
high employment density, another density
高就业密度也对此有所帮助，就业密度是衡量密度的另一个指标
measurement. High employment density can
。 高就业密度有
support good transit as people often
利于良好的公共交通，因为人们经常
commute to work, creating a demand for
通勤上班，从而产生对
transit service. Another great example
公共交通服务的需求。 巴黎是
of what I would consider optimal density
我认为密度达到最佳水平的另一个绝佳例子
is Paris. Its canonical building type
。
along Houseman Boulevards is around six
豪斯曼大道沿线的典型建筑类型约为
stories, but the current height limit is
六层，但目前的高度限制为
37 m, pretty close to Washington's 40 m
37 米，与华盛顿 40 米的限制非常接近
limit. Again, this level of density can
。 同样，这种密度可以
support an excellent rail transportation
支撑一个优秀的轨道交通
system and forms the framework for some
系统，并为
of the world's most charming streets and
世界上一些最迷人的街道和
neighborhoods. The point here is that
街区奠定基础。 关键在于，
you don't actually need massive towers
你其实并不需要建造高耸入云的摩天大楼
to achieve perfect transit
才能实现完美的交通
accessibility. Paris's metro system is
便利性。 巴黎的地铁系统
great and it's not that much worse, if
很棒，尽管车站周围的人口密度不同，但它并不
at all, than Hong Kong's, despite the
比香港的地铁差多少，甚至可能更差
stations. And I'm looking forward to the
。 我很期待
Hong Kong versus Paris debate in the
在评论区看到关于香港与巴黎的辩论
comments. And while you're there,
。 顺便一提，您也可以点
consider liking and subscribing. I
赞和订阅。 我本来
wouldn't ask except it actually helps
不会问的，但这确实有助于
the channel achieve its mission of
该频道实现其
democratizing city planning knowledge.
普及城市规划知识的使命。
Thanks. Now, there are other ways of
谢谢。 现在，
thinking about best density without
除了
using transit as a guide. There's a guy
以公共交通为指导之外，还有其他方法可以思考最佳密度。 有个叫
Christopher Alexander who wrote an
克里斯​​托弗·亚历山大的人写了一本
influential book called a pattern
很有影响力的书，叫做《模式
language. It details certain patterns or
语言》。 它详细介绍了
recipes for good buildings and cities.
优秀建筑和城市的某些模式或模式。
One of his most cited patterns is called
他被引用最多的模式之一被称为
fourstory limit. He believes that if
四层极限。 他认为，即使
you're living on the first, second,
你住在一楼、二楼、
third, or fourth story, you can still
三楼或四楼，你仍然可以通过
your window. Any higher and you start to
窗户与地面、街道生活和自然环境建立合理的联系。 再高一点，你就会开始
feel isolated and feel those negative
感到孤立，并感受到那些负面的
psychological effects. While I'm not
心理影响。 虽然我并不
entirely convinced that there's some
完全相信
sound science about the four-story limit
四层楼的限制是有科学依据的
exactly, I can see his point. Tall
，但我能理解他的观点。
towers do not serve street life nor
高楼大厦既不服务于街头生活，也不能将
connect people to it. Now, that's not to
人们与街头生活联系起来。 当然，这并不是
say that I hate towers. They can be a
说我讨厌高塔。 在交通便利的地区，它们可以成为
great way of housing a lot of people in
安置大量人口的好方法
transit-rich areas. They may provide
。 它们或许能提供
affordable housing, something that
经济适用房，而这正是
Washington DC and Paris sorely lacks,
华盛顿特区和巴黎严重缺乏的，
but I'd say that if we're searching for
但我认为，如果我们追求的是
pure optimal density, then you really
纯粹的最佳密度，那么像巴黎这样的城市绝对
can't go wrong with something like
不会出错
Paris. Now, there's also an argument to
。 现在也有人认为，
be made that you don't really need
你并不需要像
like our two examples. A city can have
我们举的两个例子那样，在整个城市中保持一致的密度。 一座城市可以拥有
lowdensity suburbs and towering office
低密度郊区和高耸的
buildings, but what needs to happen is
办公楼，但关键在于，
you need to have transit supportive
你需要在
density around those stations. This is
这些车站周围建立有利于公共交通的密集区域。 这就是
why most of the sources for this video
为什么本视频的大部分资料来源
are from researchers looking at transit
是研究以公共交通为
oriented development and planners who
导向的开发的研究人员和制定
develop standards for good transit
良好以公共交通为
oriented development. I have a whole
导向的开发标准的规划人员。 我专门制作了一个关于以
video on the topic of transit oriented
公共交通为导向的
development and I suggest you check it
开发项目的视频，建议你去看一下
out. I guess my diplomatic answer to
。 对于“
what the optimal density for a city is
城市的最佳密度是多少”这个问题，我的外交辞令大概是这样的
goes something like this. You need many
。 你需要许多
areas of transit supportive density to
交通便利、密度高的区域来
create a robust network of highfrequency
构建强大的高频
transit lines. Outside of those areas,
公交线路网络。 在这些区域之外，
density can be lower, but if you go too
人口密度可以较低，但如果密度
low, like car dependent sprawl, you get
过低，例如依赖汽车的城市扩张，就会出现
long commutes, pollution, and ugly
通勤时间长、污染和
cities. We can't have that. Not from a
城市丑陋等问题。 我们不能允许这种情况发生。 不是来自
channel called City Beautiful. Like I
名为“美丽城市”的频道。 正如我一
said at the beginning, best can be hard
开始所说，最好的很难
to define as it can mean something
定义，因为它对
different to everyone. For my money
每个人来说意义都不同。 不过就我个人而言
though, and if you allow me to switch
，如果允许我
topics for a second, Tom Scott might be
暂时换个话题，汤姆·斯科特可能是
one of the best content creators out
目前最优秀的内容创作者之一
there. For 10 years, he posted weekly
。 十年来，他每周都会发布
videos on geography, history, science,
关于地理、历史、科学
and more. Then he took a muchneeded
等方面的视频。 然后他好好
break. But now he's back and he's
休息了一会儿。 但他现在回来了，正在
touring England. You guys don't know how
英格兰巡回演出。 你们不知道
hyped I was that he was back. I've had a
他回归时我有多兴奋。 我有幸
chance to meet and chat with Tom on a
见过汤姆几次面，和他聊过天，
couple of occasions and he was just
他真是个很
lovely. It definitely was not a don't
可爱的人。 这绝对不是那种“不要和
meet your heroes moment. Okay, brag
偶像见面”的时刻。 好了，炫耀
over. Anyway, he's doing a new series
完毕。 总之，他正在制作一个新系列节目，
where he visits every county in England,
走遍英格兰的每个郡，感觉就像
and it's like he never left, and I
他从未离开过一样，我
highly recommend you check him out. Tom
强烈推荐大家去看看。  Tom
posts all of these videos early over on
很早就把这些视频发布到
Nebula. Nebula is a creatorowned
Nebula 上了。  Nebula 是一个创作者拥有的
streaming video service where Tom Scott
流媒体视频服务平台，
and I and others post videos early and
我和 Tom Scott 以及其他用户都可以在这里提前发布视频，而且
ad free. We've actually got a ton of
没有广告。 实际上，Nebula 上也有很多关于
urbanism content over on Nebula, too.
城市规划的内容。
We've got channels like Not Just Bikes,
我们有像 Not Just Bikes、
City Nerd, Downey Live, Wendover
City Nerd、Downey Live、Wendover
Productions, and my channel as well. I
Productions 这样的频道，还有我的频道。 我甚至在
series over there called Great Cities,
那里还有一部名为《伟大城市》的独家星云原创系列片，
which chronicles the most important
记录了世界各大城市最重要的
pieces of infrastructure in the world's
基础设施
greatest cities. You will never be
。 你永远不会感到
bored. Another great thing about Nebula
无聊。  Nebula 的另一个优点
is that many of us, including me, post
是，包括我在内的许多人都会提前将
our YouTube content to Nebula early.
我们的 YouTube 内容发布到 Nebula 上。
Like I mentioned, I actually post my
正如我之前提到的，我通常会
videos one full video ahead. That means
提前发布一整期视频。 这意味着，
if you see a New City, beautiful video
如果你在 YouTube 上看到一个关于新城市的美丽视频
on YouTube, the next video is already up
，那么下一个视频已经在
on Nebula. I even have a Nebulaon
Nebula 上发布了。 我甚至还建了一个 Nebulaon
Discord server where you can chat about
Discord 服务器，你可以在那里比
the video long before YouTube
YouTube
commenters. Those videos also don't have
评论者更早地讨论这个视频。 这些视频也没有
the YouTube ads. Nebula is completely
YouTube 广告。  Nebula 完全
adfree. You can get all of this for a
没有广告。 所有这些东西，
surprisingly affordable price. And when
价格都出乎意料地实惠。 当
you sign up at my link, nebula.tv/
您通过我的链接 nebula.tv/citybutul 注册时
citybutul, you'll get 50% off an annual
，即可享受年度订阅 50% 的折扣
subscription. My channel will even get a
。 只要你保持订阅状态，我的频道还能获得
portion of that subscription fee as long
一部分订阅费
as you stay subscribed. So, it's one of
。 所以，这是
the best ways to support me and this
支持我和这个频道最好的方式之一
channel. Nebul's also offering lifetime
。  Nebul 还为
memberships for people who want to go
那些想要全力
above and beyond in their support of my
支持我的
channel and the platform. I love that we
频道和平台的人提供终身会员资格。 我很高兴我们
have a couple of different ways to allow
有几种不同的方式让
people to share their support. So, go
人们表达他们的支持。 所以，
click on the link and start exploring
点击链接，即可
England with Tom Scott early and ad
与汤姆·斯科特一起提前开始探索英格兰，而且没有广告
free.
干扰。